The first epistle general of John, chapter 1.
That which was from the beginning, which we
have heard, which we have seen with our
eyes, which we have looked upon, and our
hands have handled, of the word of life.
For the life was manifested, and we have
seen it, and bear witness, and show unto
you that eternal life, which was with the
Father, and was manifested unto us.
That which we have seen and heard, declare
we unto you, that ye also may have
fellowship with us.
And truly, our fellowship is with the Father,
and with His Son, Jesus Christ.
And these things write we unto you, that
your joy may be full.
This then is the message which we have
heard of Him, and declare unto you, that
God is light, and in Him is no
darkness at all.
If we say that we have fellowship with
Him, and walk in darkness, we lie, and
do not the truth.
But if we walk in the light, as
He is in the light, we have fellowship
one with another, and the blood of Jesus
Christ His Son cleanseth us from all sin.
If we say that we have no sin,
we deceive ourselves, and the truth is not
in us.
If we confess our sins, He is faithful
and just to forgive us our sins, and
to cleanse us from all unrighteousness.
If we say that we have not sinned,
we make Him a liar, and His word
is not in us.
Chapter 2.
My little children, these things write I unto
you, that ye sin not.
And if any man sin, we have an
advocate with the Father, Jesus Christ the righteous.
And He is the propitiation for our sins,
and not for ours only, but also for
the sins of the whole world.
And hereby we do know that we know
Him, keep His commandments.
He that saith, I know Him, and keepeth
not His commandments, is a liar, and the
truth is not in him.
But whoso keepeth His word, in him verily
is the love of God perfected.
Hereby know we that we are in Him.
He that saith, He abideth in Him, ought
himself also so to walk, even as He
walked.
Brethren, I write no new commandment unto you,
but an old commandment, which ye had from
the beginning.
The old commandment is the word which ye
have heard from the beginning.
Again a new commandment I write unto you,
which thing is true in him and in
you.
Because the darkness is past, and the true
light now shineth.
He that saith he is in the light,
and hateth his brother, is in darkness even
until now.
He that loveth his brother abideth in the
light, and there is none occasion of stumbling
in him.
But he that hateth his brother is in
darkness, and walketh in darkness, and knoweth not
whither he goeth, because that darkness hath blinded
his eyes.
I write unto you, little children, because your
sins are forgiven you for his name's sake.
I write unto you, fathers, because ye have
known him that is from the beginning.
I write unto you, young men, because ye
have overcome the wicked one.
I write unto you, little children, because ye
have known the Father.
I have written unto you, fathers, because ye
have known him that is from the beginning.
I have written unto you, young men, because
ye are strong, and the word of God
abideth in you, and ye have overcome the
wicked one.
Love not the world, neither the things that
are in the world.
If any man love the world, the love
of the Father is not in him.
For all that is in the world, the
lust of the flesh, and the lust of
the eyes, and the pride of life, is
not of the Father, but is of the
world.
And the world passeth away, and the lust
thereof.
But he that doeth the will of God
abideth for ever.
Little children, it is the last time.
And as ye have heard that an Antichrist
shall come, even now are there many Antichrists,
whereby we know that it is the last
time.
They went out from us, but they were
not of us.
For if they had been of us, they
would no doubt have continued with us.
But they went out, that they might be
made manifest, that they were not all of
us.
But ye have an unction from the Holy
One, and ye know all things.
I have not written unto you, because ye
know not the truth, but because ye know
it, and that no lie is of the
truth.
Who is a liar, but he that denieth
that Jesus is the Christ?
He is an Antichrist, that denieth the Father
and the Son.
Whosoever denieth the Son, the same hath not
the Father.
But he that acknowledgeth the Son hath the
Father also.
Let that therefore abide in you, which ye
have heard from the beginning.
If that which ye have heard from the
beginning shall remain in you, ye also shall
continue in the Son and in the Father.
And this is the promise that he hath
promised us, even eternal life.
These things have I written unto you concerning
them that seduce you.
But the anointing which ye have received of
him abideth in you, and ye need not
that any man teach you.
But as the same anointing teacheth you of
all things, and is truth, and is no
lie, and even as it hath taught you,
ye shall abide in him.
And now, little children, abide in him, that
when he shall appear we may have confidence,
and not be ashamed before him at his
coming.
If ye know that he is righteous, ye
know that every one that doeth righteousness is
born of him.
Chapter 3.
Behold, what manner of love the Father hath
bestowed upon us, that we should be called
the sons of God?
Therefore the world knoweth us not, because it
knew him not.
Beloved, now are we the sons of God,
and it doth not yet appear what we
shall be.
But we know that when he shall appear
we shall be like him, for we shall
see him as he is.
And every man that hath this hope in
him purifieth himself, even as he is pure.
Whosoever commiteth sin transgresseth also the law, for
sin is the transgression of the law.
And ye know that he was manifested to
take away our sins, and in him is
no sin.
Whosoever abideth in him sinneth not.
Whosoever sinneth hath not seen him, neither known
him.
Little children, let no man deceive you.
He that doeth righteousness is righteous, even as
he is righteous.
He that committeth sin is of the devil,
for the devil sinneth from the beginning.
For this purpose the Son of God was
manifested, that he might destroy the works of
the devil.
Whosoever is born of God doth not commit
sin, for his seed remaineth in him.
And he cannot sin, because he is born
of God.
In this the children of God are manifest,
and the children of the devil.
Whosoever doeth not righteousness is not of God,
neither he that loveth not his brother.
For this is the message that ye heard
from the beginning, that we should love one
another, not as Cain, who was of that
wicked one, and slew his brother.
And wherefore slew he him?
because his own works were evil, and his
brother's righteous.
Marvel not, my brethren, if the world hate
you.
We know that we have passed from death
unto life, because we love the brethren.
He that loveth not his brother abideth in
death.
Whosoever hateth his brother is a murderer, and
ye know that no murderer hath eternal life
abiding in him.
Hereby perceive we the love of God, because
he laid down his life for us, and
we ought to lay down our lives for
the brethren.
But whoso hath this world's good, and seeth
his brother have need, and shutteth up his
bowels of compassion from him, how dwelleth the
love of God in him.
My little children, let us not love in
word, neither in tongue, but in deed and
in truth.
And hereby we know that we are of
the truth, and shall assure our hearts before
him.
For if our heart condemn us, God is
greater than our heart, and knoweth all things.
Beloved, if our heart condemn us not, then
have we confidence toward God.
And whatsoever we ask, we receive of him,
because we keep his commandments, and do those
things that are pleasing in his sight.
And this is his commandment, that we should
believe on the name of his Son, Jesus
Christ, and love one another, as he gave
us commandment.
And he that keepeth his commandments, dwelleth in
him, and he in him.
And hereby we know that he abideth in
us, by the Spirit which he hath given
us.
Chapter 4.
Beloved, believe not every spirit, but try the
spirits, whether they are of God.
Because many false prophets are gone out into
the world.
Hereby know ye the Spirit of God.
Every spirit that confesseth that Jesus Christ is
come in the flesh, is of God.
And every spirit that confesseth not that Jesus
Christ is come in the flesh, is not
of God.
And this is that spirit of Antichrist, whereof
ye have heard that it should come, and
even now already is it in the world.
Ye are of God, little children, and have
overcome them.
Because greater is he that is in you,
than he that is in the world.
They are of the world, therefore speak they
of the world, and the world heareth them.
We are of God.
He that knoweth God, heareth us.
He that is not of God, heareth not
us.
Hereby know we the spirit of truth, and
the spirit of error.
Beloved, let us love one another.
For love is of God, and every one
that loveth is born of God, and knoweth
God.
He that loveth not, knoweth not God.
For God is love.
In this was manifested the love of God
toward us, because that God sent His only
begotten Son into the world, that we might
live through Him.
Herein is love, not that we loved God,
but that He loved us, and sent His
Son to be the propitiation for our sins.
Beloved, if God so loved us, we ought
also to love one another.
No man hath seen God at any time.
If we love one another, God dwelleth in
us, and His love is perfected in us.
Hereby know we that we dwell in Him,
and He in us, because He hath given
us of His Spirit.
And we have seen, and do testify, that
the Father sent the Son to be the
Saviour of the world.
Whosoever shall confess that Jesus is the Son
of God, God dwelleth in him, and he
in God.
And we have known and believed the love
that God hath to us.
God is love, and he that dwelleth in
love dwelleth in God, and God in him.
Herein is our love made perfect, that we
may have boldness in the day of judgment.
Because as He is, so are we in
this world.
There is no fear in love.
But perfect love casteth out fear, because fear
hath torment.
He that feareth is not made perfect in
love.
We love him, because he first loved us.
If a man say, I love God, and
hateth his brother, he is a liar.
For he that loveth not his brother, whom
he hath seen, how can he love God,
whom he hath not seen?
And this commandment have we from him, that
he who loveth God love his brother also.
Chapter 5.
Whosoever believeth that Jesus is the Christ, is
born of God.
And everyone that loveth him that begat, loveth
him also that is begotten of him.
By this we know that we love the
children of God, when we love God, and
keep his commandments.
For this is the love of God, that
we keep his commandments.
And his commandments are not grievous.
For whatsoever is born of God, overcometh the
world.
And this is the victory that overcometh the
world, even our faith.
Who is he that overcometh the world, but
he that believeth that Jesus is the Son
of God?
This is he that came by water and
blood, even Jesus Christ, not by water only,
but by water and blood.
And it is the Spirit that beareth witness,
because the Spirit is truth.
For there are three that bear record in
heaven, the Father, the Word, and the Holy
Ghost, and these three are one.
And there are three that bear witness in
earth, the Spirit, and the water, and the
blood, and these three agree in one.
If we receive the witness of men, the
witness of God is greater.
For this is the witness of God, which
he hath testified of his Son.
He that believeth on the Son of God
hath the witness in himself.
He that believeth not God hath made him
a liar, because he believeth not the record
that God gave of his Son.
And this is the record, that God hath
given to us eternal life, and this life
is in his Son.
He that hath the Son hath life, and
he that hath not the Son of God
hath not life.
These things have I written unto you that
believe on the name of the Son of
God, that ye may know that ye have
eternal life, and that ye may believe on
the name of the Son of God.
And this is the confidence that we have
in him, that if we ask anything according
to his will, he heareth us.
And if we know that he heareth whatsoever
we ask, we know that we have the
petitions that we desired of him.
If any man see his brother sin a
sin, which is not unto death, he shall
ask, and he shall give him life.
For them that sin not unto death, there
is a sin unto death.
I do not say that he shall pray
for it.
All unrighteousness is sin, and there is a
sin not unto death.
We know that whosoever is born of God
sinneth not, but he that is begotten of
God keepeth himself, and that wicked one toucheth
him not.
And we know that we are of God,
and the whole world lieth in wickedness.
And we know that the Son of God
is come, and hath given us an understanding,
that we may know him that is true.
And we are in him that is true,
even in his Son Jesus Christ.
This is the true God, and eternal life.
Little children, keep yourselves from idols.
Amen.